So, let's remember how we defined our ranking function.
我们回想以下 我们是如何定义排名函数的
So, we said we're going to have a time
我们说过 要有一个时间步骤
step. We're going to keep going through steps to
我们将一直按步骤执行
get more accurate rankings. But initially, we're going to give
来获得更准确的排名 但我们要初始化
every rank 1 divided by the number of pages. Before I called that
每个排名为 1 除以页数 之前我称之为大写 N
capital N. I'm going to use npages as a more Pythonic variable name for that.
现在我要使用 npages 作为一个更加 Pythonic (Python 风格) 的变量名称
And we updated the rank at time step t by adding
我们在 t 步骤 更新排名 通过添加
the probability that the random surfer starts over and
随机浏览者 重新开始和随机选择
randomly picks that page. So, that's 1 minus d,
该页面的概率 所以 这里是 1-d
is the probability of starting over, divided by npages,
是重新开始的概率 除以 npages
how many pages there are. And remember that d
即页面数量 记住 d
is our damping constant, and we'll decide that d
是我们的阻尼常数 我们决定 d 为 0.8
is 0.8. That's the damping constant. We add to
这就是阻尼常数 我们将这些累加到
that the sum that we get of all the ranks, all the pages that link to this URL.
我们得到的链接到此 URL 的所有页面的排名总和
We add up d times the previous iterations. So,
我们加上之前迭代的 d 倍 所以
it's going to be d times rank on step t minus
它将在该页面的步骤 t-1 的 d 次排名
1 of that page. But we want to divide that by
但是我们要将其除以
the number of outlinks from p. So, it's starting
p 的外链数量 所以 它开始
to look more like Python code. We want to simplify
看起来更像 Python 代码了 在转化为
it a little bit before we get to Python code.
Python 代码之前 我们还要将其简化一点
And the first thing we're going to do to simplify
我们要做的第一件 来简化它的事情是
it, is observe that. Well, we have this t parameter.
观察到 我们有这个 t 参数
But we only ever use the very previous one. So, we
但是我们只是需要使用上一个 所以我们
don't really need to keep track of the rank value for
其实不需要跟踪所有不同 t 值
all of the different t values. We just need to keep
的 rank 值 我们只需要
track of the previous one. When we did Fibonacci, we kept
跟踪前一个 当我们做 Fibonacci 时 我们
track of current and next in variables. And that allowed us
跟踪当前和下一个变量 这使我们
to keep track of the previous and the previous previous Fibonacci
跟踪前一个和前一个的前一个 Fibonacci 数
numbers. What we want to do with ranks is something similar.
我们对排名的想法是类似的
So, we're going to use the variable ranks to keep track of
所以 我们将使用变量 ranks 来跟踪
the current ranks. And as we compute the new
当前的排名 当我们计算新的排名时
ranks, we're going to use the variable newranks. So, we'll
我们将使用变量 newranks 所以 我们将
use ranks, this corresponds to the ranks at time
使用 ranks 对应步骤 t-1 时的排名
t minus 1, the ranks of the previous iteration.
也就是上一次迭代的排名
And we'll have a variable newranks, which is the
并且 我们会有一个变量 newranks 其表示
ranks at time t. And the reason we need
t 步骤时的排名 我们需要这两个变量
both of those. As we update the rank from
的原因是 当我们更新每个页面
each page. So we're going to go through the pages,
的排名 我们遍历这些页面
recomputing its rank. We can't lose the previous one. We
重新计算其排名 我们不能失去前一个 我们
still need to get rank at the previous step for that
仍然需要在该页面的上一步获得排名
page. If we use the one that we got this time,
如果我们使用这一次我们得到的排名
that would distort the results. It would mean that the order
就会扭曲结果 这将意味着
that we update the ranks for changes the results. So, we
我们更新排名的顺序会改变结果 所以我们
don't want the results to depend on the order that we
不希望结果依赖于我们浏览页面的顺序
go through the pages. That's why we need to keep track
这就是为什么我们需要跟踪
of both the previous values, which will be used for ranks
的两个先前的值 分别对应
t minus 1 and the newranks. Once we have
t-1 时的排名和新排名 一旦我们
done that, we don't need the t parameter anymore.
做完这些 我们就不再需要 t 参数了
What we are going to do is change this rank,
我们将要做的是改变这个排名
the rank at time t is going to be the value
步骤 t 的排名将是 newranks 的值
of newranks. And the value of rank at time
而 t-1 步骤的排名
t minus 1, that's the value of ranks. The other
是 ranks 的值 另一个
change I slipped into this. Before we had parentheses
我在这里做出的改动是 之前这里是小括号
here and I've changed them to square brackets. And square,
我已经把它们改成了方括号
square brackets should give you the idea that well, this might
方括号应该会给你一个想法 这可能
be a data structure that we're indexing. And that's correct. We
是我们索引的数据结构 这个想法是对的 我们
want to index the data structure. And we want to index
想索引数据结构 我们想要由
it by the URL that we're looking for. And the Python dictionary
我们正在查找的 URL 来索引 而 Python 字典
provides a great way to do that. At the end of
提供了一个很好的方式来做到这一点 最后
this will be a Python dictionary. And that's exactly what we want.
这将是一个 Python 字典 这正是我们想要的
So, I think we're ready to start looking at the code.
所以 我想我们已经准备好开始看代码了
We've written this formula. It's still a mix of math and Python.
我们已经写了这个公式 它仍然是数学和 Python 的混合
But we're going to turn this into the code for computing the page ranks.
但是我们将把它转化为用于计算页面排名的代码